scientists may have proven sentience
within the disembodied brains grown in a
Petri dish by making them play 1970s
video games hi welcome back to man-made
Horrors Beyond Comprehension the brain
organoids which are made from stem cells
from human skin tissue and encouraged to
become neural tissue display complex
interaction the neurons learn and grow
and actually form structure is very
similar to an early human brain as well
as having brain waves similar to a
premature baby however in order to test
whether or not these brain waves
indicate thought scientists decided to
hook them up to a computer chip by
immersing the brain organoids in a
virtual world they're able to watch them
grow and learn they even learn to play
Pong faster than our current AI models
interestingly enough without the
feedback teaching them that they're
winning the game they were unable to
learn showing that the brains are
actually processing feedback this
ability to learn has raised ethical
questions about how aware the brains are
of their own reality while growing in a
Petri dish interestingly enough the
capacity for the brains to communicate
with us also gives us the opportunity to
see if they are suffering or how they
feel about this new world that they've
been grown in come back next time where
I tell you about how we popped one of
these in a mouse skull and it took over
the mouse